# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

# **Tamal Chowdhury**

### **Profile:**

Deep Learning Researcher

An autodidactic and passionate Deep Learning practitioner and researcher. Proficient in using state of the art approaches for developing intelligent systems and with a dream to decipher the cornerstone of General Intelligence.

#### **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:**

 B. Tech in Electronics and Communication Engineering National Institute of Technology, Durgapur

Higher Secondary
 Board: West Bengal Board of Higher Secondary Education

Secondary
 Board: West Bengal Board of Secondary Education

Email: tgchowdhury101@gmail.com Phone: +91-9647128980, 8617363783 Address: 566/7, Kalyangarh, North 24

Parganas, PIN: 743272, West Bengal,

India

2016-2020

GPA: 8.27

2015

Percentage: 90.2

2013

Percentage: 89.4

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

 Data Science Analyst Accenture Al

Project Linked Person
 Indian Statistical Institute, Kolkata

June 2021 - Present

September 2020 – June 2021

#### **RESEARCH EXPERIENCE:**

- Project Linked Person at ISI Kolkata (2020-2021)
  - 1. Developed an end-to-end system for remote heart rate detection from RGB video of a subject using image processing, Eulerian video magnification technique and 1D CNN.
  - 2. Developed a novel Deep Learning method for Brain Computer Interfacing (BCI) system towards digit recognition and classification using EEG signals
  - 3. Working on Deep Learning based Drug Generation and Repurposing techniques towards developing a faster and more efficient drug discovery pipeline
  - 4. Worked on the development of a Remote Intelligent Baby Monitoring System.
- Research Projects at NIT Durgapur (2016-2020)
  - 1. Developed a novel framework for Autonomous Brain MRI segmentation using Convolutional Neural Network and Mathematical Morphology
  - 2. Developed a new learning framework for ischemic stroke lesion segmentation
  - 3. Developed a novel Deep learning approach towards Breast Lesion Segmentation in Ultrasound Images
- Distance Research Project at Oxford University
  - 1. Developed a novel Deep Learning based solution towards autonomous detection of various skin cancers (fine-grain object recognition).

#### **Skills:**

- Programing Languages: Python, C
- Programing Basics: Data Structure and Algorithms
- Data Science: Data Analysis, Visualization, Interpretation
  Digital Image Processing, Digital Signal Processing, Computer Vision, NLP

Machine Learning: Regression, Classification, Clustering, Ensemble Modeling, Bayesian Networks.

Experienced with classical ML algorithms such as Decision Trees, Random Forest, K-NN, SVM and others

Deep Learning: Statistical Theory of Deep Learning, Neural Networks (Dense Networks, Convolutional Networks, Recurrent Networks), Generative Modeling and State of the art techniques.

Frameworks: PyTorch, Keras, Scikitlearn with descent knowledge of other Data Science libraries

Cloud Computing Platform: Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Azure, Paperspace

Embedded System and Robotics: Arduino Programming, Embedded System

#### **Publications:**

- 1. Contact-Less Heart Rate Detection in Low Light Videos, accepted in **ACPR 2021** (**Authors: Tamal Chowdhury**, Sukalpa Chanda, Saumik Bhattacharya, Soma Biswas and Umapada Pa)
- Exploring the Correlation between Deep Learned and Clinical Features in Melanoma Detection, accepted in MIUA 2021 (Authors: Tamal Chowdhury, Angad R.S. Bajwa, Tapabrata Chakraborty, Jens Rittscher, Umapada Pal)
- 3. DCINN: Deformable Convolution and Inception Based Neural Network for Tattoo Text Detection through Skin Region accepted in ICDAR 2021 (Authors: Tamal Chowdhury, Palaiahnakote Shivakumara, Umapada Pal, Tong Lu, Ramachandra Raghavendra, Sukalpa Chanda)
- 4. MhURI: A Supervised Segmentation Approach to Leverage Salient Brain Tissues in Magnetic Resonance Images, accepted in **Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine (Authors:** Palash Ghosal, **Tamal Chowdhury**, Amish Kumar, Ashok Kumar Bhadra, Jayasree Chakraborty, Debashis Nandi)
- 5. CSNet: A New DeepNet Framework for Ischemic Stroke Lesion Segmentation, accepted in **Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine (Authors:** Amish Kumar, Neha Upadhyaya, Palash Ghosal, **Tamal Chowdhury,** Dipayan Das, Amritendu Mukherjee, Debashis Nandi)
- 6. Analysis of Multi-Class Classification of EEG signals using Deep Learning on MUSE Dataset, accepted in ICPRAI 2020 (Authors: Dipayan Das, Tamal Chowdhury, Umapada Pal)
- 7. Breast Lesion Segmentation in Ultrasound Images Using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks, accepted in CALCON 2020 (Authors: Dipannita Ghosh, Amish Kumar, Palash Ghosal, Tamal Chowdhury, Anup Sadhu and Debashis Nandi)

# **Personal Projects and Hackathons:**

- Dual Axis Solar Tracker Using Arduino
- Medical Assistance ChatBot using Seq2Seq Model
- Implemented a vanilla Generative Adversarial Network (GAN) on CIFAR-10 dataset.
- 82% accuracy in Analytics Vidya's Ship Classification Hackathon (Within top 150).
- 84.05% accuracy in ZS Associate's Data Science Hackathon (Within top 200).
- 95.5% accuracy in Machine Hack's News Category Prediction Hackathon (Within top 10).

### **Certifications:**

• Indian School of Ethical Hacking (05/2018 – 07/2018): Short term course on Machine Learning

• Ardent Computech (05/2018 – 07/2018): Short term course on Embedded Systems

# **Position of responsibility:**

- R&D Head: Math's and Tech Club of Nit Durgapur
- Member of The Organizing Committee of Avishkar, The Tech Fest, NIT Durgapur

## **Hobbies and Interests:**

- Al, General Intelligence and Cognitive Neuroscience
- Content Writing
- Kaggle Data Science Competitions
- Reading Books and Blogs
- Music composition